<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:ns3="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:ns4="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:ns5="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ONF Surveyors</title>
	<ns0:link href="https://onfsurveyors.com.au/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onfsurveyors.com.au/</link>
	<description />
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 03:21:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<ns1:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</ns1:updatePeriod>
	<ns1:updateFrequency>
	1	</ns1:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onfsurveyors.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/cropped-image_17__1_-removebg-preview-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>ONF Surveyors</title>
	<link>https://onfsurveyors.com.au/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Navigating Property Boundaries: Why Boundary Surveys Matter</title>
		<link>https://onfsurveyors.com.au/navigating-property-boundaries-why-boundary-surveys-matter/</link>
					<comments>https://onfsurveyors.com.au/navigating-property-boundaries-why-boundary-surveys-matter/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator>adon_dev</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 07:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category>Uncategorized</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onfsurveyors.com.au/?p=2862</guid>

					<description>&lt;p&gt;At&amp;#160;ONF Surveyors, we are your trusted partner for property, boundary, and residential surveying services. With a focus on delivering accurate results and tailored assessments, we incorporate the latest technologies to provide efficient and cost-effective solutions. Since our founding in 2002, our team of directors and surveyors has been dedicated to offering the highest standard of&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://onfsurveyors.com.au/navigating-property-boundaries-why-boundary-surveys-matter/"&gt;Navigating Property Boundaries: Why Boundary Surveys Matter&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://onfsurveyors.com.au"&gt;ONF Surveyors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
										<ns3:encoded>
&lt;p&gt;At&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/TEssMb7LPJRhH4dGA"&gt;ONF Surveyors&lt;/a&gt;, we are your trusted partner for property, boundary, and residential surveying services. With a focus on delivering accurate results and tailored assessments, we incorporate the latest technologies to provide efficient and cost-effective solutions. Since our founding in 2002, our team of directors and surveyors has been dedicated to offering the highest standard of service to clients across the Sunshine Coast, Brisbane, and Kingaroy. In this article, we will explore the importance of boundary surveys for property owners. Emphasising the need for accurate boundary determination to prevent disputes, understand property rights, and make informed decisions regarding land use, development, and property transactions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Boundary Surveys Matter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-full"&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" width="880" height="588" src="https://onfsurveyors.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/surveyor-using-a-surveying-equipment.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2864" srcset="https://onfsurveyors.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/surveyor-using-a-surveying-equipment.jpg 880w, https://onfsurveyors.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/surveyor-using-a-surveying-equipment-300x200.jpg 300w, https://onfsurveyors.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/surveyor-using-a-surveying-equipment-768x513.jpg 768w, https://onfsurveyors.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/surveyor-using-a-surveying-equipment-366x245.jpg 366w, https://onfsurveyors.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/surveyor-using-a-surveying-equipment-255x170.jpg 255w" sizes="(max-width: 880px) 100vw, 880px" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Accurate boundary determination is vital for property owners. A boundary survey precisely identifies the property lines and establishes legal boundaries. By conducting a thorough boundary survey, you can avoid potential disputes with neighbors over encroachments and ensure that your rights are protected. Understanding the exact location of your property boundaries is crucial when making decisions about land use, construction projects, and property improvements. Additionally, when engaging in property transactions, having a verified boundary survey provides confidence to buyers and lenders.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Boundary Survey Process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The boundary survey process involves several key steps that our experienced surveyors at ONF Surveyors follow diligently. We begin by researching historical records, deeds, and surveys related to the property. This information helps establish a baseline for the survey.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://dictionary.cambridge.org/us/dictionary/english/fieldwork"&gt;Fieldwork&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;is then conducted, utilising advanced equipment such as total stations and GPS technology to accurately measure and mark the boundaries. Our surveyors also consider physical markers, existing structures, and natural features to ensure precise boundary determination. Finally, we compile the collected data into a comprehensive survey plan, including boundary markers, and any relevant information for future reference.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ONF Surveyors: Delivering Accurate Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-full"&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="https://onfsurveyors.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/shutterstock_527683066.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2866" srcset="https://onfsurveyors.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/shutterstock_527683066.jpg 1000w, https://onfsurveyors.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/shutterstock_527683066-300x200.jpg 300w, https://onfsurveyors.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/shutterstock_527683066-768x512.jpg 768w, https://onfsurveyors.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/shutterstock_527683066-366x244.jpg 366w, https://onfsurveyors.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/shutterstock_527683066-255x170.jpg 255w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At ONF Surveyors, we understand the critical role that boundary surveys play in property matters. That’s why we incorporate the latest surveying technologies to ensure accurate results. Our capabilities include subdivision and boundary realignment surveys, easements and covenants, level and detail surveys, and boundary identification surveys. With a focus on delivering the highest standard of service, our team of directors and surveyors continuously strive to improve our systems and services, tailoring our assessments to individual projects to provide efficient and cost-effective solutions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact ONF Surveyors Today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Boundary surveys are essential for property owners to avoid disputes, and make informed decisions regarding land use and transactions. At ONF Surveyors, we specialise in property, boundary, and residential surveying, offering accurate results and comprehensive survey plans. Trust our experienced team to incorporate the latest technologies and provide tailored assessments for your projects. Contact us at Brisbane&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="tel:0733763003"&gt;07 3376 3003&lt;/a&gt;, Sunshine Coast&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="tel:0754220200"&gt;07 5422 0200&lt;/a&gt;, Kingaroy&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="tel:0741622647"&gt;07 4162 2647&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;or visit our website&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://onfsurveyors.com.au/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to learn more. You can find our Brisbane office located at Unit 2A/38 Limestone Street, Darra our Maroochydore office at Unit 4B/32 Aerodrome Road and our Kingaroy office conveniently located at Shop 3 Circular Pl, Kingaroy. Experience the ONF Surveyors difference and ensure the integrity of your property boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://onfsurveyors.com.au/navigating-property-boundaries-why-boundary-surveys-matter/"&gt;Navigating Property Boundaries: Why Boundary Surveys Matter&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://onfsurveyors.com.au"&gt;ONF Surveyors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</ns3:encoded>
					
					<ns4:commentRss>https://onfsurveyors.com.au/navigating-property-boundaries-why-boundary-surveys-matter/feed/</ns4:commentRss>
			<ns5:comments>0</ns5:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel></rss>